activecollab.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy · ActiveCollab

###### Principles

What follows are the principles regarding the data we collect. 

5.1 What personal data we collect about you

We collect your data only when you provide it to us while using our Services, and when our third-party processors, which we have appropriate contracts with that are subject to EU regulations, provide it to us. We encourage you to read below our detailed list of all the data we collect and which purposes we do it for. 

Many of our features and options require some personal data (essential features and options like communication email and invoicing details), but for non-essential features, you can choose not to provide us your personal data (username, profile picture, etc.). Bear in mind that, in certain situations, providing data is required by law. 

**Account and profile information**  
When you register for a trial account, we ask for your email only. When you switch to a paid account, we need more information for billing purposes. In both cases, we collect data for account personalization - it is optional for you to add a profile photo and other details. 

**Your content provided through our websites**  
We collect the content you upload while using our websites, including our social media channels. This refers to the feedback you give on our surveys, promotions, events. 

**Data needed for support channels**  
When you experience a problem or need assistance, you may need to contact our Support. Whatever the context is (email, ticket, social media channels, audio/video call, chat), you will be asked to provide information related to the problem. This means providing any type of data (contact information, problem explanation, screenshots, etc.) which is necessary for troubleshooting and which may speed up the process of resolving the issue. This process is defined in our Terms of Service, and any issue-related details are necessary in order to provide you with our support services. 

**Billing information**  
When you register for a paid account, we collect your payment and billing details through secure payment processing services. We collect information about you or your billing representative: billing information (name and contact information), payment address and payment details (credit card or bank account number). 

**Your content uploaded through our products**  
Using our products (web app, desktop app, mobile apps) means uploading your content for collaboration purposes.  
The content you upload on your cloud account is stored on our servers, and only you can access it. In specific cases, when troubleshooting is needed, our Support may need to check your instance - with your explicit consent and login details. We don’t have any information about the content you upload on your self-hosted account since that content is uploaded to your own servers. 

**Your use of the Services**  
We collect information about you while you’re using our Services. We basically keep track of your visits and interactions with our Services. This information includes the features and add-ons you use, details about your collaborating activity, details about your device and operating system, browser type. 

**Cookies and other tracking technologies**  
We and our third-party processors use cookies and other tracking technologies to recognize you across different Services and devices and to provide better experience and functionality. 

**Data from other sources**  
We also receive data about you from third-party services. This happens when you link or integrate our Services with a third-party service, or when you give consent to other services to use your information. For example, we use third-party service for payment and billing purposes, or our advertising and market research partners provide us with information about your interests and engagements with our Services and online ads. You can see the list of all our third-party processors in section 5.5 of this policy. 

5.2 How we use your personal data

Based on the purpose, here we explain how we use your data. 

**To provide the Services and personalize your experience**  
We need your data so we can provide our Services to you. Basic activities include transaction processing, authentication, providing customer support, operating and maintaining the Services. For example, we use your email and the photo you provided to identify you to other users on your account. We also use your data to personalize your experience by offering you relevant features and making recommendations. 

**Research and development**  
We always strive to improve our Services and integrate them better with other apps you use. That means we use data we collect about how you (and other people) use our Services to shorten the onboarding process, identify trends in user behavior, and create a map of activity patterns. This helps us pinpoint the exact areas for future improvement. Along with this data, we also use all the feedback we get for precise troubleshooting and creating a more friendly and engaging user experience. We keep relying on legitimate interest when it comes to beta testers as well, and the feedback we get from them is solely for the purpose of improving and developing our services. 

**To communicate with you about the Services**  
In order for you to successfully use our Services, we create certain communications to shorten your learning curve and create a satisfactory user experience. These communications include onboarding emails, transactional emails, purchase confirmations, subscription expiration reminders, responses to comments, requests and questions, complete customer support service, technical notices and updates, security alerts, administrative messages, promotions, new features. Depending on your settings, we send you email notifications about collaborating activity on your account.   
When you sign up for our Services, you agree to these communications, and in most cases, you can’t opt-out of them. When the opt-out option is available, you will find it within the communication itself or in the settings section of your account. 

**For marketing, promotion, and engagement**  
We create promotional content that may be of specific interest to you, and that is why we send it via email or display it in our ads. This is why we use your contact information and information about how you use our Services - so the content is as relevant to you as possible. Those ads appear on different websites and platforms (like Facebook and Google). All this content has a purpose of driving engagement and helping you use our Services to the fullest. Besides emails and ads, we also create survey requests, newsletters, informational product content. 

**To provide Customer Support**  
When it comes to Support, there are different scenarios in which we need your data, e.g., to assist you with different kinds of requests and needs, to resolve technical issues you reported, to analyze crash details, to repair and improve our Services. When you give us your information, it is shared only with our experts (employees), only for the purpose of giving feedback and resolving the issues as soon as possible, as defined in our Terms of Service. 

**Security and safety reasons**  
There are situations when, for certain safety and security reasons, we need to use the data about you and your use of our Services - e.g., to verify accounts, to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity, to identify violations of our policies. 

**Legitimate interest and legal rights**  
We use your data when we need to protect our legal rights, interests, and the interests of others, as well as when we’re required by law to do so. In these cases, as always, we use your data only when necessary. 

**With your consent**  
There are specific purposes, not listed above, that require your consent so we can use data about you. We always ask for your permission in these cases (e.g., quoting you on our sales website, or publishing your customer story on our blog). When you give us consent to use your data for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but if any processing has already taken place, it will stay unaffected. 

5.3 ActiveCollab as a processor of User/Client Data

As specified in Article 28 of the GDPR, the relationship between the controller and the processor has to be made in writing. The electronic form is also acceptable under subsection (9) of the same Article. Our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy serve as your data processing agreement. ActiveCollab will process your data based on your written instructions as the data controller unless required by law to act without such instructions. 

You may upload and transmit your data inside our Services. We do not view nor control such data, and we process it on behalf of you in accordance with our Terms of Service. You have the responsibility to ensure that all the data you upload and transmit has all the relevant consents or a suitable privacy policy in place to cover the transmission and processing. This means that it is also your responsibility to ensure that any private, sensitive, or confidential information you upload in connection with your use of the Services does not become available or disclosed to unauthorized or unintended viewers. We expressly disclaim any responsibility for your unauthorized or unpermitted sharing, distribution, publication, or display of any private, sensitive, or confidential information. 

5.4 How we share your data

When we collect or process your data, our employees here at ActiveCollab are in charge of handling it. Depending on the context, purpose, and data type, members of different teams are in charge. All our employees have gone through extensive and proper training programs, so they are aware of relevant privacy principles and law requirements. 

We will never share your data, unless in the ways discussed below. 

**Sharing with other Service users**   
When you sign up and start using our Services, other users on your account will be able to see your data. Some of the collaboration features display some or all of your profile information. For example, when you comment on a task, we email subscribers to the task with the comment, your name, and your profile photo. 

**Sharing with third-party apps**   
We work with third-party apps to make our Services more integrated and collaboration-friendly for you, our users. When you add new functionality or change the behavior of the Services by enabling third-party apps, you may give those apps access to your data, such as name, email, and any content you decide to share. What you share with those apps and on their websites is governed by their policies, not this one. 

**Sharing with third-party widgets**   
Some of our Services contain widgets and social media features. They collect your IP address, details of the page you are visiting on the Services, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These widgets and features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Sharing with law enforcement**   
We will share your data in the situations when: we need to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including meeting national security requirements; enforce our Terms of Service, Privacy Policy and other agreements; protect the security and integrity of our products and services; we believe need to respond to an emergency related to preventing someone’s death or serious injury; we need to protect ActiveCollab, our customers, or the public from harm or illegal activities. 

**Sharing with your consent**   
When you give us your consent, we will share your data with third parties. For example, we might share, with your consent, your name and the name of your company as part of the testimonial on our website. You can revoke your consent at any given moment, just contact us and send us your request. 

**Sharing in business transfers**   
If a merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of ActiveCollab to another company happens, you will be notified via email. This will inform you about the choices you may have regarding the situation. 

**Sharing with third-party service processors**   
In the next section, we listed all the third-party processors we have contracts with. We work with them to provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, payment processing, and other services for us, which may require them to access or use some data about you. When these Service Providers require to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under instruction from us, including abiding by policies and procedures designed to protect your information. 

5.5 Service Processors

Sometimes we use third-party processors to process some or all of your personal data. Here we listed all of them. We made sure that we’ve signed contracts only with third-party processors who are GDPR compliant. These third-party processors have access to your personal data only to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purposes. 

**Help Scout:** our Customer Care team uses this help-desk software to stay in touch with you. This software uses only your email and name, for the purpose of us getting back to you, assisting with your requests, and resolving the issues you might have. [Here](https://www.helpscout.net/company/legal/privacy/) you can read how Help Scout deals with privacy. 

**Crisp:** this is a messaging [platform](https://crisp.chat/en/privacy/) our Customer Care team uses to chat with you. Crisp uses only your email, and we chat with you wherever you start a conversation over our website or straight from our app. The most frequent case is the need for customer support. 

**Stripe:** this tool processes your payments to us. We use it for billing purposes only. Stripe collects your payment details (credit card or bank account number), along with your name and payment address. In case payment and billing details are different, they are both collected. Also, if you’re not the one making the payment, the mentioned data of your billing representative is collected. For more information on how Stripe deals with privacy, [read this](https://stripe.com/us/privacy). 

**FastSpring:** this is a cloud-based eCommerce that we use as a billing platform. Like Stripe (mentioned above), Fastspring collects your payment details (credit card or bank account number), along with your name and payment address. In case payment and billing details are different, they are both collected. Also, if you’re not the one making the payment, the mentioned data of your billing representative is collected. For more information on how FastSpring deals with privacy, [read this](https://fastspring.com/privacy/). 

**Google Analytics:** this is a web analytics service that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the collected data to track and monitor the use of our Services. It may use the data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. For more information about Google’s privacy practices, read [this](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

**Google AdWords:** this is a remarketing service provided by Google Inc. [Here](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated) you can control the information Google uses to show you ads or make the ads more useful to you. If you want to learn more about Google’s privacy policy, follow [this link](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

**Facebook Ads Manager:** this is an advertising management [tool](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/), developed by Facebook. It’s designed for creating ads, managing when and where they’ll run, and tracking how well those advertisements are performing. Facebook can use a business’s CRM data (email, telephone number) to match it to people in their database to create a Custom Audience for advertising campaigns. Facebook Pixel Code uses cookies for advertising purposes on the Facebook advertising network. 

**MailChimp:** we use this marketing automation platform for staying in touch with you via email. This occurs when we send you our newsletter or include you in our incentive program. [This](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) is where you can read more about MailChimp’s policy. 

**Google Drive:** this is a service developed by Google, and we use it for file storage. This is the place where we temporarily keep your data for the purposes of reporting, customer care, feedback analysis, usability testing, marketing, incentive programs. For more information about Google’s security policy follow [this link](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

**Zoom:** this is a [cloud platform](https://zoom.us/privacy) we use for video calls. With your permission, sometimes we record video calls, only for the purposes of improving our customer care and sales process. Videos along with your name and number (if given) are always deleted within 2 weeks. 

**Skype:** this [software](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/PrivacyStatement) temporarily collects only your number when you leave us a message. We use that data only to get back to you and for no other reason. After a successful call, your number is deleted. 

5.6 Security

We’ve designed our platform to offer you a secure-by-default experience. When it comes to customer data security, encryption, storage, and backups, everything we do is described in our Security Policy. We encourage you to read it and contact us if you have any questions or concerns. 

In case of a data breach, we will follow the implemented procedures which ensure we will inform you and respond to the data breach in a timely manner. 

5.7 How and where we store and process your data

**Where we store and process your data**  
Personal data collected by ActiveCollab is stored and processed in the United States, Canada, France, and in Serbia, where ActiveCollab’s operating facility is located. Our primary storage locations are in Canada and the USA, with an offsite backup in France. We make sure that the data we collect under this privacy statement is processed according to the provisions of this policy, our Terms of Service, and the requirements of applicable law wherever the data is located. 

**How we handle data transfers**  
We transfer, process, and store your data from your region to Serbia or wherever our third-party processors operate, only with the purpose of providing you with our Services. Serbia is not a member of the European Economic Area, but we use a variety of legal mechanisms and contracts to ensure that your rights and protections travel and apply with your data. 

**Deleted data**  
When you cancel your account, we’ll delete all of your data in the following 30 days.
